<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daniel Glauber</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Daniel Glauber</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Daniel Glauber</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 13:51:31 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Providence Maps</title>
      <link>/project/maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 13:51:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/maps/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DocASAP Wrap-up</title>
      <link>/post/docasap-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 11:27:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/docasap-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The day we arrived at DocASAP, we were assigned our first task: build the desks that we&amp;rsquo;d be using for the rest of the summer. Assembling IKEA furniture was not how I expected to start my summer internship at the health tech company, but it offered a surprisingly fun introduction to the startup lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides learning how to use a power drill (CEO Puneet Maheshwari was a great teacher), I have gained much from my experience at DocASAP. The first technical project I was assigned to was performance testing the front-end of the website. I became very familiar with the tool JMeter, a software that allows one to simulate and analyze the response times of 1000+ concurrent users accessing a website.
We were able to isolate bottlenecks in the client-server flow in order to optimize performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then I have had the chance to work on many different projects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;UX/UI review for the patient booking flow&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A database table migration, which was a nice introduction to PHP&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;SEO analysis for DocASAP&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/webhp?sourceid=chrome-instant&amp;amp;rlz=1C1RUCY_enUS695US695&amp;amp;ion=1&amp;amp;espv=2&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8#q=dr%20wheeler%20maxwell&#34;&gt;Google White Labels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Researching database configurations (master/slave vs. clusters) in preparation for a possible database restructuring&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Integrating the central database hub with external Electronic Practice Management (EPM) APIs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Refactoring the codebase of a 10000+ line backend project, which was a fascinating and challenging software engineering problem&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Creating a fun company video! As of this time, the video is still in production, but once I get word that it&amp;rsquo;s finished, I&amp;rsquo;ll share a link to it&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving out the company video, this progression of projects was an increasingly challenging yet manageable journey through the roles a developer may hold at a tech company.
Whereas before the operations of a professional software engineering team was somewhat of a mystery to me, I now feel confident that I could succeed in a professional environment such as this one.
I&amp;rsquo;m especially thankful to have had the chance to work on these last couple of projects. I feel that I have made a significant contribution to my company&amp;rsquo;s core product, which is something that not all interns are able to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wearing many hats is fairly typical for a developer at startup that is growing at the rate DocASAP is. Looking back, I am impressed by the company&amp;rsquo;s growth in just the three months that I&amp;rsquo;ve been here. Since arriving, I&amp;rsquo;ve witnessed many milestones for DocASAP, including reaching 1,000,000 appointments booked with one of our clients. The company is rapidly expanding, with new interviewees in the office every other day. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to follow the progress of DocASAP in years to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, the people that I&amp;rsquo;ve met and worked with here at DocASAP have made my time as an intern comfortable, rewarding, and fun.
The term &amp;ldquo;strong family spirit&amp;rdquo; is aptly used on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docasap.com/team&#34;&gt;DocASAP Team Page&lt;/a&gt;. The small team (~20 people here at the headquarters) and the colorful, bright, open office, replete with beanbag chairs and bouncy balls and void of cubicles (see above picture), contribute to making DocASAP a welcoming, unified work environment. Perhaps most important to me, a broke college student spending summer away from home for the first time, were the catered lunches. Every day, the company&amp;rsquo;s employees congregated in the psuedo-kitchen to eat together. Free food is great, but breaking bread allowed me to get to know a group of kind, intelligent, and humorous people I&amp;rsquo;m not soon to forget.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hi-i-m-daniel-a-developer-designer&#34;&gt;Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Daniel, a developer &amp;amp; designer.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently a student at Brown University concentrating in computer science.
This past summer I worked as a software engineering intern at &lt;a href=&#34;https://docasap.com&#34;&gt;DocASAP&lt;/a&gt;, an online platform that enables patients to book appointments with the healthcare providers of their choice.
In the past, I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with the team at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.healthmap.org/en&#34;&gt;HealthMap&lt;/a&gt; as a data science intern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides health tech, I have a passion for education in computer science with a focus on inclusion for underrepresented minorities in the field.
I work alongside other mentors on a team supported and funded by &lt;a href=&#34;https://ignitecs.withgoogle.com&#34;&gt;Google IgniteCS&lt;/a&gt; to run a coding club at a local high school in Providence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://danielglauber.online/Daniel%20Glauber%20Resume%202016.pdf&#34;&gt;You can view my full resume here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my free time, I enjoy Olympic weightlifting, playing board games with my friends, and making simple 2D games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Computer science is still magic to me; as I grow and develop more as a programmer I&amp;rsquo;m ultimately driven by the thrill of creating something fun and engaging out of nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking iMessage</title>
      <link>/project/sms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 19:35:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/sms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was the final project for my user interfaces class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my partner Kevin Cadena&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kevincadena.com&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is an interpretation of Tristan Harris&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://timewellspent.io/&#34;&gt;Time Well Spent Manifesto&lt;/a&gt; to design interfaces that are more ethical and considerate to a person&amp;rsquo;s needs and life. Along with this another initiative of the project was to rethink how we can interact with the phone in ways more native and natural to it as opposed to tapping buttons which is where the swiping interface developed from. Similarly to how &lt;a href=&#34;www.dontclick.it&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Click It&lt;/a&gt; explores hovering to interface with a web browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about the development of this project, &lt;a href=&#34;http://kevincadena.com/img/Sketching:Prototypingv2.pdf&#34;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autocorrect</title>
      <link>/project/autocorrect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 19:54:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/autocorrect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For my software engineering class I implemented an autocorrection program similar to that of Google&amp;rsquo;s search engine form. The user interface&amp;rsquo;s functions include mouseover and arrowkey suggestion selection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggestions are generated using:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prefix matching&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Levenshtein_distance&#34;&gt;Levenshtein edit distance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whitespace splitting (&amp;ldquo;mousecheese&amp;rdquo; -&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;mouse cheese&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggestions were prioritized using n-gram rankings. An n-gram is a sequence of words of length &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;. The idea behind n-gram rankings is that the likelihood of a word/suggestion to occur is dependent on the &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; words that preceed it. The fact that my ranking algorithm uses n-grams as opposed to, say, &lt;em&gt;bi&lt;/em&gt;-grams means that the ranking process is configurable to take into account any given number of preceeding words (on the live site I have it set to 5).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://apps.danielglauber.online/autocorrect&#34;&gt;Check it out!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theatre Collective</title>
      <link>/project/theatre-collective/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 11:57:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/theatre-collective/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IgniteCS - Classical Highschool Coding Club</title>
      <link>/project/ignite/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 13:40:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ignite/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Puzzle</title>
      <link>/project/go-puzzle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 23:59:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/go-puzzle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A friend recently proposed to me this logic puzzle (&lt;a href=&#34;http://ai.stanford.edu/~hdwang/puzzle2.html&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GoBang is an oriental chess game, also called 5-in-a-Row. Here we consider a modified version:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The board is a grid extending infinitely to all four directions. In each turn, player A puts two black stones on the board while player B puts down only one white stone. Player A wins if 1000 of his black stones form a consecutive line (either vertical, horizontal, or diagonal). Player B tries to block A from achieving that goal. However, player B himself can never win (i.e. the game continues even if 1000 of his white stones form a line). Show that player A has a strategy so that he can always achieve the goal and win, no matter how player B plays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided it would be a fun side project to make this into an interactive game, so here we go: &lt;a href=&#34;http://danielglauber.online/two-stones/&#34;&gt;http://danielglauber.online/two-stones/&lt;/a&gt; (note: I&amp;rsquo;ve only tested it on Google Chrome, so it may not work on other web browsers and definitely not on mobile)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to figure it out myself to be honest, so if you manage to get, say, 20 pieces in a row, send me a screenshot!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cellphone Puzzle</title>
      <link>/project/cellphone-puzzle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 23:49:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/cellphone-puzzle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The same friend also proposed to me this logic puzzle (&lt;a href=&#34;http://ai.stanford.edu/~hdwang/puzzle2.html&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose that there is a building with 100 floors. You are given 2 identical cellphones. The most interesting property of the cellphones is that every cellphone has its own &amp;ldquo;threshold&amp;rdquo; floor. Let&amp;rsquo;s call that floor N. What this means is that the cellphone will not break when dropped from any floor below floor N, but the cellphone will definitely break from any floor above floor N, including floor N itself.
For example, if the property of the cellphones is that N equals 15, those cellphones will always break on any floor higher than or equal to the 15th floor, but those cellphones will never break on any floor below floor 15. The same holds true for the other cellphone since they are identical.
These are very strong cellphones, because they can be dropped multiple times without breaking as long as they are dropped from floors below their &amp;ldquo;threshold&amp;rdquo; floor, floor N. But once an cellphone is dropped from a floor above its threshold floor it will break and may not be used again.
Your task is to figure out the threshold floor N by dropping the two cellphones off of the building. What is the minimum number of drops necessary to accomplish this goal?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I again decided it would be fun to make this into a responsive puzzle game of sorts. &lt;a href=&#34;http://danielglauber.online/cellphones/&#34;&gt;Try it out!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>